We are entering a completely new era in
personal brand building. Today, if you
want to build a lucrative personal brand
that makes millions of dollars, you
don't need to go mega viral. You don't
need millions and millions of followers.
You don't need to have made content for
10 years. All you need is to become
micro famous in your niche. This is how
all of these people have built
seven-figure businesses in just a couple
years online without ever touching
mainstream fame. Now, the truth is
building micro fame this quickly wasn't
possible just five years ago. Most
people on this list hadn't even started
posting five years ago. But, the reason
it's possible now and why so many people
are unlocking this micro fame is because
the algorithms have changed. And that
change makes right now the only time in
history where you can get famous fast
inside of a category. Now, in this
video, I'm going to break down the
playbook for how anyone watching this
can become micro famous in their niche.
I'll explain why it's possible now, what
makes it so attractive, and the exact
steps that you can follow to make it
happen for yourself. By the way, if you
don't know me, my name is Chalene. I
have a million followers. I've done
billions of views, and content is all I
do all day long. All right, before we
get into the tactics, let's just define
what being micro famous actually means.
Cuz this will really help you understand
the ultimate goal of your content
strategy. Being micro famous means that
you are the authority figure in your
category. Micro fame isn't about the
number of followers you have. It's about
your authority density per follower. And
if there was one single metric that
could compare audience value across
channels, it would be this. Imagine
there were two accounts. The first one
has 2 million followers in the sports
niche, but it's largely based on news
reporting, trends, memes, and a couple
of viral bangers based around cultural
moments. The second one only has 50,000
followers in the collectible space. But,
every single one of those 50,000 people
considers them the collectibles expert.
They trust them. They follow their
picks. And when they have a question on
collectibles, their name and face is the
first thing that pops in their head.
Now, be honest, which of these two
accounts would you say is more valuable?
Most people honestly would say the first
one. Because even though it's more
general, it has 40 times more followers
and likely gets way higher average
views. But, the truth is, in almost
every scenario, the collectibles
account, number two, will out-earn the
first one. And this is the power of
authority density. In personal branding,
dollars come from authority, which comes
from trust accrued over time. So, your
goal, if you're trying to build a super
lucrative personal brand, is to increase
the density of authority across your
audience. And it actually doesn't take
that big of an audience to be able to
build a seven-figure business. This is
exactly why buying followers or running
follower ads to grow your following is a
mistake. This is a metaphor I like to
use. Imagine you had a glass full of red
food coloring, and it was super
concentrated, very, very deep red. Every
follower you add that doesn't trust you
would be like adding clear water to that
glass. Over time, the glass fills up,
but the liquid dilutes, first turning
light red, and then pink, and then
eventually almost clear. This metaphor
is a proxy for trust dilution over time,
which is very common, but it is the
number one killer for why personal
brands stop being able to monetize. So,
if there's one metric that tells you how
valuable an audience actually is, it's
not followers, it's authority density.
And becoming micro famous is just the
exercise of maximizing this authority
density. So, here's a really quick test
you can run to just subtly gauge what
your authority density looks like. Ask
yourself this, if you polled all of your
followers and you asked them
independently, "Who is the number one
person in this niche that you trust the
most?" Would they say you? Cuz if the
answer is mostly no, you don't have a
follower problem, you have a density
problem. And everything else I'm going
to go through in this video will help
you fix that. And that will enable you
to become micro famous. All right, the
last thing I want to cover before I get
into the tactics, and this is so, so
important, is to understand why becoming
micro famous is now so much easier today
than it was five years ago. Something
structurally has changed in the way
social media works, and understanding
this is very important in helping you to
take advantage. There are three core
shifts to the algorithms and social
media design that make this fast fame
possible in this era. The first one is
what I call zero ramp virality. Just 5
years ago, there was really no ability
for you to go viral on day one of
posting. [music] You had to first build
up a following and get them to engage
with your stuff over time even have a
chance of something breaking out. Well,
today that is completely flipped. If you
make a new account on Monday and you
post a banger on Tuesday, you could have
a million views and 10,000 followers by
Wednesday. I call this zero ramp
virality. There's zero ramp required to
be able to go viral. And this is an
insane thing to unlock if you know what
you're doing. It just wasn't possible
before. Now, the second condition that
changed that makes this micro fame
process easier is called automatic
targeting. 5 years ago, social
algorithms targeting ability was nowhere
near as sophisticated as it is today.
And this just means it took a lot longer
for algorithms to understand who your
ideal viewer was supposed to be. Because
of that, you just had to post
organically for a long time to try to
hone in this audience match. Well, today
that is also completely flipped. Social
targeting precision is insanely good.
Almost right out of the box as soon as
you start posting on a new account.
Because of this, in just a couple
videos, the algorithms can very
accurately target the exact person you
want to reach with almost zero spillover
into a bad fit avatar. So, you're
getting both insane reach potential to
the exact right people almost instantly.
Now, the third condition that changed
this, and this really is the biggest
one, is the unlimited scale. Organic
content can now scale infinitely.
Before, you could post high volume like
5, 10 times a day, but you really risked
follower fatigue because the only people
that saw your stuff were followers. So,
if you just hammered post, the same
people would be seeing your stuff over
and over. Today, that is also changed.
For You feeds basically allow you to
post 10 times per day without fatiguing
your followers because they'll just show
it to a bunch of other non-followers
that are similar to the people following
you. If you add these three variables
up, it means that if you make the right
content, you can reach millions of the
right people on day one and then
continue reaching millions more like
them whenever you want. These are what I
call Goldilocks conditions when it comes
to marketing and it's why I've been
basically screaming to every business
owner I know and making these videos
with my hands like this over the last 2
years because as soon as I recognized
these conditions had changed, it becomes
the greatest marketing bet you could
possibly make to make organic video
content. So, these three conditions
multiplied together are why it's so much
easier to become micro famous now than
it was 5 years ago. And if you don't
believe me, take me as an example. Just
3 years ago, I had never posted a
short-form video. No YouTube, no
short-form, nothing. Fast forward just 3
years, I have 2 million followers, I've
done billions of views, I have my own
micro fame in literally two different
categories. I'm famous in AI and I'm
famous in marketing as well. In each of
those categories, I've built
seven-figure businesses, both of them.
All of that in 3 years from zero. That
is only possible because the conditions
have changed so that I can jump to the
top of a niche without having to wait my
turn in line. And I'm telling you, you
can do the same thing, too, by becoming
micro famous in your niche, which I'm
going to break down right now with this
tactical playbook. By the way, guys, if
you like how I'm explaining this, I've
also open-sourced my content system for
free. What I'm about to go through is
the strategy around winning and becoming
micro famous, but you're also going to
need the system for how to make the
videos. So, everything I do from ideas
to hooks to script writing to
monetization, it's all included in here
for free. You can get it at
shortformsystem.co
or check out the link in the
description. All right, now let's get
into the tactical playbook. This will
cover the strategic positioning and the
content strategy for how you become
micro famous in literally any niche. A
lot of people don't know this about me,
but I actually spend a lot of my time
helping business owners figure this out,
how to become micro famous in their
category. I've obviously done it for
myself twice in two different niches,
but I don't think you can really
pressure test a system until you apply
it to other people that aren't you. So,
this is what I've been running for
dozens and dozens of business owners
behind the scenes. A lot of people you
see dominating categories have some
version of this running or I've worked
with them directly. A good example of
this is Pat. I've been working with Pat
for about a year. He went from zero,
never making content ever, to having
over 100,000 followers total across
Instagram and TikTok, and basically
owning the backpacking review niche.
He's had many videos get over a million
views. He's done brand deals with many
of the top brands in the backpacking
space. He's launched his own backpacking
brand, which did its first launch with a
five-figure launch, and that was all in
1 year. Nobody really knows him outside
the backpacking niche, but inside he is
a top authority figure. He's micro
famous. So, this is a perfect example of
what it looks like to become micro
famous in a niche. And like I said, 12
months, zero to that. So, here's the
tactical playbook that I personally run
on all of my channels, what Pat ran
himself, and what I put the dozens of
business owners that I work with
directly through. The first part, and
this is super important, is to figure
out a unique strategic position. And
this is literally the exercise that I
ran through when I started posting on my
Callaway Marketing Instagram account
just 90 days ago. So, I'm going to take
you through the framework, and then I'm
going to show you how I applied it to
myself to grow way faster. For context,
I've gone from zero to about 60,000
followers in just 90 days. I'm growing
about 1,000 followers a day following
this playbook exactly. So, here's how
you do it. First, you take the niche and
the platform that you're playing on. So,
for me in this case, it was social media
growth on Instagram. Then you want to
come up with a unique lane within that
niche that isn't currently
oversaturated. I call this a unique
positioning angle, a UPA. And this is
ideally where you identify white space
that suits your expertise, personality,
background, and unique abilities, or
unique experience. Now, if you're
literally creating the niche, or you're
one of the first ones in this niche,
well, then this exercise is not that
difficult. All you have to do is start
making content across any of these
attributes, and you'll be good. This
would be like the settlers in the 1850s
in the US. They didn't have to be real
estate savants, they just went out
there, everything was available, they
picked their plot and they were good.
Now, on the flip side, if you're trying
to compete in a very crowded niche, this
exercise is a little bit harder and you
should spend time trying to figure out
what your unique lane is going to be.
This would be like trying to buy
beachfront property in Hawaii today.
There are still deals to be had, but you
have to really know what you're doing
and spend time carving out your thesis.
Now, when I say carve your lane, let's
get very granular. There are seven
different positioning attributes where
you can find white space to carve your
own positioning. The goal is to stack up
as many of these attributes together cuz
they multiply to create this unique
lane. Again, if you're in your own
category, you're one of the first to
make content, you might only need one of
these. If you're in a crowded niche, you
probably need a few stacked up together.
So, these are the seven unique
attributes when it comes to unique
positioning. The first one is topic
selection. So, this would be you talking
about topics in your niche that aren't
widely covered already today. So, for
example, in social media growth, this
would be like if I identified hooks were
really important as a topic, but nobody
was covering them, I could just start
talking about hooks and that would
create white space that I would fill.
The second attribute is substance depth.
So, this would be where you're talking
about common topics that are already
covered, but the value or the tactics or
the insights that you give on those
topics is just way different than
everyone else. So again, in the social
media space, it could be I've identified
hooks are important, a lot of people
already talk about it, so I don't get
any topic differentiation, but the way I
talk about it, what I say, the insights
I share are just different at a higher
value level and so that's how I
separate. The third attribute would be
unique stories or scenarios. This would
be if you have unique experience or
expertise in actually doing the thing so
that you can share that that a lot of
people don't have and couldn't copy you
on without lying. So, for example, in
the social media space, if I grew five
accounts to a million followers and not
that many people had done that, well
then I could share lessons learned and
stories that are atypical from what
people typically see and that would
create white space that I would fill.
The fourth attribute or way to separate
in positioning would be avatar
specificity. So, this would be like
you're talking to a specific unique
avatar slice that is underserved in the
niche. So, for example, in the social
media growth space, if there are a lot
of people there, but no one's talking to
mortgage brokers about social media,
that would be a unique lane or unique
avatar specificity that you would fill.
The fifth attribute would be delivery
style. So, this is your tone, your
rhythm, your speaking cadence, the way
you come off on camera. For example, to
continue this in the social media space,
let's say I saw everybody was
communicating in this like informal raw
way. Well, I could fill white space
being more professional, buttoned up,
rigid, wearing a suit, for example. The
sixth attribute is storytelling format.
So, this is pretty classic. You're
delivering storytelling formats that
aren't typically being used in your
niche. So, in the social media space,
let's say I saw everybody making these
ranking and tier lists and listical type
videos, but nobody was doing challenge
videos where they actually challenge
themselves to go zero to 100k in 30
days. I saw white space there, and so I
filled it. And then the seventh
attribute would be visual format. So,
this is that you're filming or editing
laying videos out in a way that you
typically don't see in the niche. So, to
finish the example in social media, if
everybody's shooting raw in their
bedroom, you could come more cinematic
or in a studio or just a completely
different visual delivery. So, those are
your seven options for how to find
differentiation or white space to create
your own lane in a niche. Again, the
more crowded the space is, the harder it
is to carve one of those lanes, and you
have to stack some of those together.
The more open the space is, the less you
have to do. You can just pick one, fill
it, and you'll win. So, if we think
about how I approached the social media
growth space on Instagram 90 days ago,
this is how I went through each of those
seven categories and what I thought
about with respect to if there was white
space that I could fill. And again, a
lot of this is custom to me with my
unique background and skills that I knew
I had. For you, you don't have the same
skills and background and proof as me,
so you may have to approach this
differently even if you're attacking the
social media growth space. So, like I
said, just to give context, zero to 60k
followers in 90 days, growing about
1,000 followers a day, 5.5 million views
or so total. So, that means over 1% of
people that see a video follow me. I've
driven over 20,000 collected emails and
over 100,000 in revenue during that
90-day period. I should have over
100,000 followers by the end of 2026.
Just to give you a sense of like where
I'm at and how fast it's working. Now,
here's how I thought about my
positioning across those seven buckets.
The first one is topic selection. So,
are there any topics not being covered
in the social media growth space that I
could fill? Candidly, social media
growth is very competitive. A lot of the
topics have already been covered. One
that I identified that was pretty open
was AI content workflows. So, anytime I
make a video about Claude and
Sandcastles combined, it crushes. That's
my top category, and there's a reason
for that. Huge TAM, and it's kind of
open relative to some of the other
stuff. So, that was something that I
wanted to try to differentiate on a
little bit. This alone was not going to
be my only competitive positioning
difference because I didn't want my
whole account to be about AI. But, that
was definitely something I was going to
add to the stack. Second bucket is
substance depth, right? So, this is how
I approach topics people are already
covering, but going deeper and more
value. The current state of social media
content, for the most part, is very
surface-level. You see a lot of people
being like, "Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday,
Thursday." And they're just like listing
the formats with no value at all.
Someone like Eva, Personal Brand Launch,
is actually very good at deeper
substance. She goes a level deeper than
most people, which is why she grew so
fast. She was really like the only
social media growth content channel that
did this at scale 2 years ago. That was
her significant positioning. But, I knew
I could approach it similar to her in a
different way. I could also go deeper
substance, but not copy what she was
doing, and I knew there was white space
there. So, the substance is a core
pillar where I knew I could separate
from most people. And this kind of goes
back to like my expertise background and
how I articulate things. This is a
strong suit of mine, so I knew this
would be my anchor unique positioning
differentiation. And by the way, when
you hear me break this down, you can
hear the precision that goes into this
type of strategic exercise. I'm very
strategic with how I do this. I am the
type of person you're competing against
in a very competitive niche. So, just A,
accept that there are people that think
about it at this depth. And B, the
reason why you want to work with someone
like me is cuz I'll just tell you what
the positioning should be so you can
follow it, so you can avoid the
wandering period where you don't know.
If you're not going to work with me,
there's only a handful of people in the
world that can kind of cut through the
BS and tell you how to think about it at
this level. I recommend you find one of
those and just pay them so you can avoid
the ignorance tax. All right, the third
bucket is unique stories and scenarios.
Now, I have some really great case
studies like the one I went through with
Pat that I really rarely talk about cuz
I don't like to lead with the case study
proof. It feels sleazy and salesy to me.
I also don't like layering in those
examples when you have a very small
following. Something feels incongruent
about having 5,000 followers but being
like, I helped this person grow to 100k.
It's very misaligned. So, I like to wait
to use the case studies and scenarios
until I'm a little bit bigger. So, for
that reason, I wasn't planning on using
this as a differentiation point in the
first growth phase. The fourth bucket
was avatar specificity. Now, rather than
talk broadly about social media growth
to everyone, I was going to dial in for
social media for business owners. The
thing is, there's still a lot of people
that are positioning themselves that
way, social media for business owners.
So, although that was going to be part
of how I wanted to come across, it
wasn't going to be enough
differentiation alone to separate. The
fifth bucket is delivery style. Now, I
have a pretty unique speaking cadence
and rhythm when it comes to content. I'm
very good at annunciating my words so
that clarity is maxed out. This is one
of the reasons why I've been able to
grow so fast on YouTube and it's kind of
like my calling card, right? It's just a
It's just a unique skill that I have.
Also, on the delivery side, I dress in
all black. I have this kind of like
cinematic set that is atypical from what
you typically see in social media. You
don't see people articulating things
like this at this level of depth in this
visual package. So, for all of those
reasons, delivery was also something I
thought I could separate on by just
executing in my normal style. Now, the
sixth attribute is storytelling formats.
Now, when it comes to social media,
almost all the formats have been tried
and covered. The social media niche is
really where formats get born typically.
So, I knew there wasn't going to be much
space to differentiate on this
attribute. Because of that, I was just
going to stick to what I'm good at,
breakdowns, explainers, and listicles.
Now, you can win by coming up with a
unique format no one's ever seen before,
but that quickly gets cloned and
commoditized. Just look at the Kumar
thing. And so, it's not easy to rely on
this to have consistent advantage. So,
for that reason, I just wasn't counting
on any lift here. And then lastly was
visual format. Visually, I prefer the
premium, high-polish, high-aesthetic,
cinematic execution. That's just what my
eye suits. It's what I do on YouTube.
It's what I do on my tech videos. Lots
of the gurus talk about how this doesn't
work and raw is the only way to win.
It's nonsense. I don't believe that at
all. Raw can work, the cinematic can
work, it can all work. It's just about
what are you contrasting against
relative to the field. So, the good news
is most people try to do the raw stuff
on social media. I knew I could easily
win with cinematic and polished, and so
that's how I wanted to come across
visually. So, if you add those up, I had
significant differentiation on substance
and delivery style. I was going to come
across differently visually, and I had a
one-topic bucket that most people
weren't covering. If you multiply those
together, it makes me one of one in the
niche. And so, that doesn't mean I'm
guaranteed to win, but at least if I
execute on the strategy correctly,
there's open white space that I can run
and fill into and then grow faster. Now,
people can try to copy the visual
execution, and they already have, right?
The style I have, people try to copy
that. But the thing is, when you copy a
visual style that most people think of
one person for, most of the value
accrues back to me. When they see that
style, they think of me in this niche.
So, if you copy it, you don't really get
the lift. [music] Things like substance
and delivery style are way less easy to
copy, so there's a moat there as well.
Now, I will say, if you're watching
this, unless you're in the social media
growth space, which I know a lot of
people are who are watching this, if
you're outside that, there's a good
chance your niche is way less
competitive than social media growth.
The two niches I play in, social media
growth and AI, are two of the most
competitive niches on the internet. I
would say fitness and maybe like cooking
or recipes or also super competitive,
although those TAMs are massive. But
most other niches, there are small
pockets where they aren't that
competitive. So, you have a ton of room
to come up with your own UPA. You don't
really need to go so crazy like I did.
Now, the best way to come up with what
the options are that you could use for
each of those buckets is called
transpositioning. So, what I recommend
is first you look at your niche and try
to figure out what the baseline is
that's working on your niche. And you
could use sandcastles.ai for that. Just
build a channel list and then you can
kind of look at what's working. But
then, if you can't find differentiation,
what you want to do is go to similar or
distant niches that are far from yours,
look at what's working for them, and
then bring some of that over to yours.
This is called transpositioning.
Typically, you're not going to outrun
somebody by cloning the person that's in
your niche. If they're already better
than you and they have a compounding
advantage, you're typically not going to
outrun by copying them. So, what you
want to do is go somewhere else. If
you're in social media growth, go to
like the vintage hat niche, see what
they're doing at the top of that niche,
and if there's something different that
you don't see in social media, bring
that over. That's really where the alpha
and sauce is. And this is why it's
actually really helpful to study people
outside of your niche. Now, the best way
to get exposed to those is you can look
at collections on sandcastles. We've
hand-curated 105 different collections
across formats, [music]
signature series, editing styles, and
visual hooks. Inside of each collection
are between five and 10 of the
best-performing videos for that type
across all niches. So, there's probably
500 to 1,000 different videos that are
hand-curated. These are top videos that
you can watch and get exposed to
different types of execution, different
types of formats that are outside your
niche. I find this to be one of the
fastest ways to just get exposure to
top-performing videos without having to
reset your own social algorithms. So, if
you want to check that out, I've linked
a couple of the collections below so you
can see how they work. All right, so
that is really the first piece around
strategic positioning. And I find that
to be really, really helpful, especially
if you're playing in a competitive
niche. If you do the work up front to
define what that white space lane could
be, Then, all you have to do is execute
on the content strategy, and you will
grow a lot faster. Now, the next piece
is how you actually make the content.
Like, what is your content mix across
different topics that will help you
execute on that positioning? And I
recommend every single person run what I
call the 3-2-1 content strategy. Now,
I've built a ton of different content
strategies, and like I said, worked with
dozens and dozens of business owners
testing all this. I'm very confident the
3-2-1 is the best for most people. So,
the 3-2-1 is very simple. You're going
to come up with three different topic
buckets that you make two videos each
per week. So, that'll be six of your
seven weekly videos if you're posting
once a day. The seventh video is going
to be what I call the chaos agent. This
can be a triple down on any of the three
buckets, or just something random you
saw in some other niche that you just
want to try, right? It's meant to be
controlled chaos to inflict random tests
so you can experiment outside of the
buckets. For the three main buckets, one
of your buckets is going to be more
broadly positioned. So, it's still going
to be a topic that will accrue trust and
authority to you in the niche, but it's
meant to be a little bit broader so you
can have a chance at virality to bring a
ton more people into the zeitgeist. The
other two buckets are going to be more
narrowly positioned. These will be
specific buckets that are very valuable
to your specific ideal viewer avatar and
buyer. And so, these can come from pain
points you know they have, outcomes you
know they want, things that have come
from client conversations, or topics
you've seen covered that you know matter
for your ideal viewer. And those two
narrow buckets are not meant to go super
viral. Instead, they're meant to go
deeper and drive more conversion and
trust accrual per view. So, three
buckets, two videos each, one chaos
agent. 3-2-1. Now, to figure out what
these three buckets are going to be, you
can either randomly guess, so you take a
piece of paper, you write down all the
most important topics you think matter,
you pick three, you randomly guess, you
make videos across those three for a few
weeks, let the data tell you, and then
iterate. That's the less data-backed way
to do it, but like the quickest, just
random guess. The other way to do it,
which is what I recommend, is you
research the top competitors in your
niche between 25,000 and 250,000
followers. You do a deep analysis, which
I'll walk through how to do in a second.
You let that tell you which topic
buckets are working best, and then you
pick three from there. Now, the fastest
way to do this, this exercise, which I
recommend everyone do, you first go to
Sandcastle's, and you need to build a
channel list of your top competitors in
your niche. If you don't know who they
are, just go to Sandcastle's, go to the
channels tab, go to describe, and just
type in the topics that you cover, or
whatever you describe your niche as.
Sandcastle's will suggest the top
channels that fit that description. You
can either add all of them into the
channel list just by pressing add all or
the plus, or you can pick one of them
that you recognize, add that one in, and
then press the arrows that say more like
this, which will hone the search to be
closer to that person. If you don't want
to do it this way, you can also scroll
on your For You page, or look at your
explore page until you see videos come
up that you like. Take that person's
channel profile, go to the channels tab,
either search for them or add the URL
in, and build your channel list that
way. Either way, you want to build this
channel list of competitors. Every
single person that makes content has
done this. This is the most valuable
exercise you could do. Your goal is
about 20 to 25 competitor channels
between 25 and 250,000 followers in that
Sandcastle's watch list. Now, once you
have that done, go to the videos tab,
you will automatically see all of the
videos from those channels listed in the
videos tab. I want you to go up to sort,
press outlier score. I want you to go to
post date, and do last 3 months. And
then for engagement rate, put the
minimum bound at 2%, which filters out
any of the paid brand deals. Now, you've
got the top performing videos
organically from the last 3 months from
all those competitors in one place. Now,
you can easily open each of these in a
new tab and watch them. If you just
hover over, you can see how to do that.
But, the much faster way is to deep
analyze all these videos, and let Claude
tell you what the best performing topics
are. So, to analyze, you can hover over
a video and click the analyze button one
by one, or you can go to bulk analyze at
the top, type in either 50 or 100, which
will be 100 videos analyzed at once, and
it will automatically deep analyze the
top 100, or whatever number you put in.
Doing this will spend one credit per
video, so 50 is a good number to start
with. Now, let that run for 5 to 10
minutes and you will see the little
green analyze badge on all the videos.
It'll say done in the upper right. Once
it's done, go to export and export that
data into a CSV. You will now have all
of the videos you deep analyzed, the
transcript, the topic, the hook, the
format, the storytelling structure,
literally all the data you would need
about those videos. You're going to grab
that, you're going to drag them to a new
chat in Claude, you're going to use the
Fable 5 model, and you're going to run
this prompt. My goal is to build a
high-value authority audience in insert
niche, put your niche there. I want you
to build a visual distribution that
breaks down the top-performing topic
buckets across all of the videos in the
file I gave you. This is a deep analysis
pull of the top X videos, however many
you did, from the top channels in my
niche. Screen out any video that doesn't
make sense for my niche, if it's about
their personality or whatever, screen
those out. My goal is to come up with
one broader-reaching viral topic bucket
and two more narrow topic buckets for
the avatar that I'm trying to cover. You
can add more information about your
avatar to help clarify it, I recommend
as much detail as possible, and then
press run. This will run for 5 minutes
and it will give you a visual
distribution breaking down the topic
performance for all of those videos.
This will tell you exactly what topics
are working best, and you can pick three
from there. Now, based on the three you
pick, you're going to run the 3-2-1
strategy. You're going to do that for 2
weeks, and then you're going to come
back and you're going to re-evaluate how
it's working. If you notice some of the
buckets are not performing at all across
any of the four videos you made across
those 2 weeks, you're going to kill that
bucket, and you're going to promote a
new bucket, either from the initial
research list or something that your
random controlled chaos agent surfaced,
[music] you can bring that to a new
bucket. This is the fastest way to use
data to make sure your allocation of
time towards content is working the
best. Now, once you have done these two
strategic exercises, number one, you
identified your unique strategic
position, and number two, you mapped out
the 3-2-1 strategy, you'll only have
three questions left. Number one is how
do I actually make the winning video?
Like, I have the topics, but how do I
write the hooks? How do I write the
substance? How do I edit it? Right?
That's That's bucket one. Number two, if
you're busy or a business owner, how do
I build a team that can actually help me
do these videos for me? And number
three, how do I evaluate which videos
are working and not? And specifically
the ones that are working, how do I
extract the learnings to apply to my
future videos? Those are the three big
questions you'll have once you solve
these two strategic pieces. Now, for
those first two questions, how do I make
the videos? How do I make a team? This
is what I help people with in SFA. I
work one-on-one with business owners to
help you make winning videos, help you
build a team. You come in, I review your
videos, get you good, and then you
graduate out. So, if you want to work
with me for that, I've got a link below.
Now, for the third question, how do I
know what's working? This is where you
want to use the Sandcastles dashboard.
If you click the dashboard tab, you will
notice, once you verify your social
channels, we are running a content
strategy report for you every 7 days. If
you scroll to the bottom of the page,
you'll see the top-performing topics,
hooks, formats, and scriptwriting
techniques automatically run for your
last batch of videos. You can click on
any of those subcategories, and to the
right side we will tell you specifically
what is working and what's not working,
what you should keep doing, and what you
should not keep doing. So, once you have
your channels verified and you turn that
on, it will be a machine that just
surfaces you insights for what's working
and not working automatically. You can
see it in the dashboard whenever you
want. We also send you an email every
time we run that report. This has been
hands-down the favorite feature we've
ever launched. I look at this dashboard
literally every day because it tells me
what to make and what not to make. If
you want to learn more about how to get
the dashboard set up and how I'm using
it, like what I'm looking at in the
metrics, I've got a tutorial linked
below for you. All right, guys, that is
all I've got for this video. As
promised, I wanted to go deep down the
rabbit hole on how to actually build
your strategy around becoming micro
famous in any category. First, we talked
about what being micro famous is and the
conditions that changed in the social
media world that make it possible to do
this faster now. Then, as promised, we
went through what I think are the two
most valuable strategy exercises you
could do. One, defining your unique
strategic positioning, and two, defining
what those buckets would be for the 321
content strategy. Obviously, there's a
lot more to it from there in terms of
how to actually make the videos and
improve them over time. If you want to
work directly with me on that, I've got
links below. If you don't, I recommend
you linking up with some coach that can
help you cuz it will speed up your cycle
of iteration. If you're a business owner
or a serious creator, you can probably
tell this will be one of the most
valuable channels you could watch in
terms of how to learn content to grow
your business. So, make sure to like,
make sure to subscribe, and definitely
drop a comment on what you're struggling
with on the content front. I look at
those comments to help guide the next
video, so it's super helpful when you
do. I've got a bunch of free stuff in
the description to help you get started
with a lot of these things, so make sure
to check out all of that. I'm trying my
best to help people grow as fast as
possible. All right, we will see you
guys on the next one. Peace.